DANIEL KELLEY, PMP, PMI-ACP

www.linkedin.com/in/daniel-kelley1 • https://github.com/DK-2021

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Adaptable, organized and dependable US Army Special Operations veteran. Someone who is always seeking to optimize a process or develop a solution to a problem. Transitioning into software engineering with a fundamental understanding of full stack software development. Possess and have maintained a Secret Clearance for more than ten years.

RELEVANT CERTIFICATIONS

- Project Management Professional (PMP), 2021
- Project Management Institute Agile Certified Practitioner (PMI-ACP), 2021
- Microsoft Certified Azure Fundamentals (AZ-900), 2021
- Microsoft Technology Associate Software Development Fundamentals (MTA 98-361), 2021
- NC State University Artificial Intelligence Academy Foundations Course, 2021

TECHNICAL AND SOFT SKILLS

- C#/HMTL/JavaScript/CSS
- MVC ASP .NET
- GitHub/Git

- Microsoft SQL Server
- Microsoft Azure
- Microsoft Office Suite
- Project Management
- Staff Management
- Human Dynamics

EXPERIENCE

Microsoft Software and Systems Academy

Cloud Application Development Student

January 2022 - May 2022

- Selected for a highly competitive program that supports transitioning service members as they gain the professional and technical knowledge necessary to enter the technology industry.
- Studied in **Cloud** Application Development, learning to design, build, and support applications and programs.
- Gained fundamental skills in **C#, SQL, JavaScript, CSS, HTML**, **Github** and Object-Oriented Programming.
- Learned conceptual frameworks for Web Application Development, **ASP.NET MVC**, and **Azure Application Development**.
- Built, modified, and ran more than 100 queries against **T-SQL** databases via **SQL Server Management Studio** for data analysis and interpretation.

95th Civil Affairs Brigade (Army Special Operations)

Assistant Operations Supervisor

October 2020 - January 2022

- Assumed the Operational Supervisor position for four months during a company realignment; maintained both positions for four months and managed 15 coworkers to meet all organizational directives.
- Managed the company's classified personnel recovery database; increased the company's compliance from 80% to 100% when audited by a third-party.
- Published over 35 organizational bulletins that were distributed to more than 200 coworkers weekly; informed coworkers of company-wide events and notified of career enhancing opportunities.

Civil Affairs Specialist

October 2017 - October 2020

- **Coordinated** four humanitarian assistance programs valued at **\$45,000**; enabled the U.S. Embassy access to three strategic locations in Trinidad and Tobago.
- Managed the expenses of \$20,000 USD worth of organizational funds while working
 internationally; utilized the funds appropriately enabling the team to increase its overall capacity to
 achieve objectives.
- Managed and coordinated over 200 tasks to different teams in support of organizational functions; all tasks' deadlines were met and adherence to the enterprise's readiness model standard was maintained

PROJECTS

- Random Restaurant Picker C#, SQL, XML, XAML (https://github.com/DK-2021/RandomRestaurantPicker) A team project that leveraged an API of a given location to help select a type of restaurant to eat at based on certain user preferences. Utilized GitHub with teammates, allowing for each member to work with the project's latest version.
- **Personal Webpage** HTML, CSS, JavaScript, GitHub, Visual Studio Code, MS Paint (https://dk-2021.github.io/MyWebsite/) Using GitHub as a host, based on a website template, reconfigured the HTML, CSS and JavaScript to be used as a personal website. The website described my abilities, links to work and experience.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, **Criminal Justice**, University of Massachusetts, MA

May 2011